Love is a hustle.
Anora is a drama, comedy, romance film directed by Sean Baker.
A young sex worker from Brooklyn gets her chance at a Cinderella story when
she meets and impulsively marries the son of an oligarch.
Once the news reaches Russia, her fairytale is threatened as his
parents set out to get the marriage annulled.
Ani, played by Mikey Madison.
Ivan, played by Mark Eydelshteyn.
Igor, played by Yura Borisov.
Toros, played by Karren Karagulian.
Garnik, played by Vache Tovmasyan.
Lulu, played by Luna Sofía Miranda.
Anora is a 2024 American romantic comedy-drama film written,
directed, produced, and edited by Sean Baker.
It stars Mikey Madison as Anora "Ani" Mikheeva, a lap dancer from New York who
marries the wealthy son of a Russian oligarch played by Mark Eydelshteyn.
The supporting cast includes Yura Borisov, Karren Karagulian, Vache
Tovmasyan, Darya Ekamasova, and Aleksei Serebryakov.
Anora premiered at the 77th Cannes Film Festival on May 21, 2024, where
it received critical acclaim and won the Palme d'Or.
It was released theatrically on October 18, 2024 by Neon.
The film grossed $58.2 million worldwide against a $6 million
budget, making it Baker's highest-grossing film.
Anora received numerous accolades.
The film was named one of the top ten films of 2024 by the National
Board of Review and the American Film Institute.
The film received six nominations at the 97th Academy Awards, winning five for Best Picture, Best
Director, Best Actress (Madison), Best Original Screenplay, and Best Film Editing.
It is one of only four films to win both the Palme
d'Or and the Oscar for Best Picture.
Anora also received seven nominations at the 78th British Academy Film Awards, winning two; five at the 82nd Golden Globe Awards; three at
the 31st Screen Actors Guild Awards; and one at the 70th David di Donatello for International Movie, which the film won.
The film explores themes of new year's eve, new york
city, marriage, boardwalk, baptism.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.